Inventory of the Jack Chen papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jack Chen papers
1913-1995
1927-1980
2013C15
Chen, Jack, 1908-
7 oversize boxes (3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives
Drawings, cartoons, writings, correspondence, and clippings, relating to political conditions in China, foreign relations of China, and world politics. Includes political cartoons by Jack Chen published in the international communist press.
Access
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2013.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Chinese artist and author; resident in the Soviet Union, Great Britain and the United States.
Scope and Content of Collection
Drawings, cartoons, writings, correspondence, and clippings, relating to political conditions in China, foreign relations of China, and world politics. Includes political cartoons by Jack Chen published in the international communist press.
China--Emigration and immigration.; China--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons.; Drawings.; World politics--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons.
- Albums of cartoons, 1927-1966
  - 1927-1933, Wuhan and Moscow (Box 5)
  - 1933-1936, Moscow (Box 5)
  - 1936-1938, includes the worldwide tour of his anti-Fascist exhibit (Box 2)
  - 1938-1940s, London (Box 2)
  - 1939-1947, London, Shanghai, Stockholm, and Finland (Box 2)
  - 1940-1944, Daily Worker, London (Box 2)
  - 1950-1960s, including the Xinjiang trip in 1957 and Hong Kong trip in 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - 1957-1962, Beijing (Box 2)
  - 1950-1966, Beijing (Box 2)
- Original cartoons, published in Peking Review (Beijing Review)(40 cartoons), undated (Box 1)
- Album of articles written between 1947 and 1949 (Box 3)
- Album containing various responses after Chen's arrival in U.S. in 1971, including the controversy over his appointment as a consultant to the New York State Education Department (Box 6)
- Album of lecture tours on U.S. campuses, undated (Box 1)
- Albums of reviews on Jack Chen's books on China (2 albums), 1980 (Box 1)
- Album of Chen's exhibits in the U.S. between 1973 and 1980 (Box 3)
- English edition of the Chen family history, Return to the Middle Kingdom: One Family, Three Revolutionaries, and the Birth of Modern China, 1970s (Box 4)
- A Year in Upper Felicity: Life in a Chinese Village During the Cultural Revolution, 1970s (Box 4)
- Inside the Cultural Revolution, 1970s (Box 4)
- Album of Jack Chen's drawing in Progress of China's Industrial Cooperatives, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
- Clippings, articles, and miscellany, 1960s-1970s (Box 3)
- Photographs, articles, letters, and clippings, undated (Box 7)